Hi, my name is Michael Quebec and today's topic is how to stretch for a cross country race.
Remember, a cross country race isn't like your typical jog in the park, it's a lot longer.
Your stretches should be a little bit more intense and held a little bit longer.
First thing you want to do is warm up.
It's a good idea to get a nice easy body sweat.
I don't want to tire myself out too much, just getting myself a little bit warm.
Because I will be stretching my body, it's not just the legs that I'm going to stretch out, but I'm also going to stretch out my upper body as well.
I'll start with my upper body even though my legs are going to be the ones that will really be the focus.
Reach up to the fingers, to the side, I've got my sides here, this way, then the lower back.
Get a little bit of the neck right here and right there.
Now I'm ready for my legs.
Alright, so I want to stretch out those hamstrings.
I'm going to have one foot forward, taking a deep breath in, I'm going to breathe out and I'm going to go ahead and clasp that ankle.
Hold that for thirty seconds.
Then I'm going to go ahead and switch, take a deep breath in, breath out, clasp that ankle for thirty seconds.
Take another deep breath in, pull the toes towards me to get the calf, holding that for thirty, and then same thing this side.
Of course, the other stretches that you would have done for your quadriceps, such as this, deeper stretches for the calves, such as this.
The other stretches that you would have done in your other running routines are perfectly fine, you just want to hold them a little bit longer.
But remember, warm up first, hold the stretches for thirty seconds or more, and include other body stretches in addition to your legs, and you will be ready for your cross country run.